cyngn.com 2015-04-01

# Cyanogen - Cyanogen Privacy Policy

**UPDATED: JUNE 3RD, 2014.  
**

Your privacy is important to Cyanogen Inc. and our affiliates ("Cyanogen"), so we've developed a Privacy Policy that covers how we collect, use, disclose, transfer, and store your information. Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with our privacy practices.   

### 1\. Collection and Use of Personal Information

Personal information is data that can be used to identify or contact a single person. 

You may be asked to provide your personal information anytime you are in contact with Cyanogen. We may also combine it with other information to provide and improve our products, services, content, and advertising. You are not required to provide the personal information that we have requested, but, if you chose not to do so, in many cases we will not be able to provide you with our products or services or respond to any queries you may have. 

Here are some examples of the types of personal information Cyanogen may collect and how we may use it. 

#### What Personal Information We Collect

When you create an account (such as a CyanogenMod Account or a CyanogenMod Forum Account), register your devices or products, purchase a device or product, download a software update, contact us or participate in an online survey, we may collect a variety of information, including your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, contact preferences, and credit card information. 

#### How We Use Your Personal Information

  * The personal information we collect allows us to keep you posted on our latest product announcements, software updates, and upcoming events.
  * We also use personal information to help us create, develop, operate, deliver, and improve our products, services, content and advertising, and for anti-fraud purposes.
  * From time to time, we may use your personal information to send important notices, such as communications about purchases and changes to our terms, conditions, and policies. Because this information is important to your interaction with Cyanogen, you may not opt out of receiving these communications.
  * We may also use personal information for internal purposes such as auditing, data analysis, and research to improve Cyanogen's products, services, and customer communications.

#### Collection and Use of Non-Personal Information

We also collect data in a form that does not, on its own, permit direct association with any specific individual. We may collect, use, transfer, and disclose non-personal information for any purpose. The following are some examples of non-personal information that we collect and how we may use it: 

  * We may collect information such as occupation, language, zip code, area code, unique device identifier, location, and the time zone where your product or device is used so that we can better understand customer behavior and improve our products, services, and advertising.
  * We may collect information regarding customer activities on our website and from our other products and services. This information is aggregated and used to help us provide more useful information to our customers and to understand which parts of our website, products, and services are of most interest. Aggregated data is considered non-personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

If we do combine non-personal information with personal information the combined information will be treated as personal information for as long as it remains combined. 

### 2\. Cookies and Other Technologies

Our website, services, interactive applications, email messages, and advertisements may use "cookies" and other technologies such as pixel tags and web beacons. These technologies help us better understand user behavior, tell us which parts of our website people have visited, and facilitate and measure the effectiveness of advertisements and web searches. We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as non-personal information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy. 

Cyanogen and our partners also use cookies and other technologies to remember personal information when you use our website, online services, and applications. Our goal in these cases is to make your experience with Cyanogen more convenient and personal. Knowing your contact information, product serial numbers, and information about your computer or device helps us register your products, personalize your experience and provide you with better customer service. 

If you want to disable cookies and you're using the Safari web browser, go to Safari preferences and then to the privacy pane to disable cookies. For other browsers, check with your provider to find out how to disable cookies. Please note that certain features of our website will not be available once cookies are disabled. 

As is true of most websites, we gather some information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type (and version) and language, Internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. 

Since our products and services reside on or are integrated with mobile and tablet devices, we may collect device-specific information including hardware model name, operating system version (including both Android and CyanogenMod versions), name of your mobile carrier, and unique device identifiers. This information may be associated with your CyanogenMod Account. 

We use this information to understand and analyze trends, to administer the site and our services, to learn about user behavior on the site and services, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Cyanogen may use this information in our marketing and advertising services. 

In some of our email messages, we use a "click-through URL" linked to content on our website. When customers click one of these URLs, they pass through a separate web server before arriving at the destination page on our website. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked in this way, you should not click text or graphic links in the email messages. 

Pixel tags enable us to send email messages in a format customers can read, and they tell us whether mail has been opened. We may use this information to reduce or eliminate messages sent to customers. 

### 3\. Disclosure to Third Parties

At times, Cyanogen may make certain personal information available to strategic partners that work with Cyanogen to provide products and services, or that help Cyanogen market to customers. For example, when you purchase and activate your device, you authorize Cyanogen and your carrier to exchange the information you provide during the activation process to carry out certain services. If you are approved for service, your account will be governed by Cyanogen, your device manufacturer and your carrier's respective privacy policies. Personal information will only be shared by Cyanogen to provide or improve our products, services and advertising; it will not be shared with third parties for their marketing purposes unless you expressly consent to such sharing. 

#### Service Providers

Cyanogen shares personal information with companies who provide services such as information processing, extending credit, fulfilling customer orders, delivering products to you, managing and enhancing customer data, providing customer service, assessing your interest in our products and services, and conducting customer research or satisfaction surveys. These companies are obligated to protect your information and may be located wherever Cyanogen operates. 

#### Others

It may be necessary − by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from public and governmental authorities within or outside your country of residence − for Cyanogen to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for purposes of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or appropriate. 

We may also disclose information about you if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms and conditions or protect our operations or users. Additionally, in the event of a reorganization, merger, or sale we may transfer any and all personal information we collect to the relevant third party. 

### 4\. Protection of Personal Information

Cyanogen takes the security of your personal information very seriously. While we use industry standard security measures to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information we collect, Cyanogen cannot guarantee complete security. 

Cyanogen encrypts many of our services using Transport Layer Security (TLS) to protect your personal information. Some of our services require TLS and will not function without it. When your personal data is stored by Cyanogen, we use computer systems with limited access housed in facilities using physical security measures. Cyanogen does not store plain text passwords. 

When you use some Cyanogen products, services, or applications or post on a Cyanogen forum, chat room, or social networking service, the personal information you share is visible to other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. You are responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these instances. For example, if you list your name and email address in a forum posting, that information is public. Please take care when using these features. 

#### Access to Personal Information

You can help ensure that your contact information and preferences are accurate, complete, and up to date by logging in to your account at[https://account.cyanogenmod.org](https://account.cyanogenmod.org/). For other personal information we hold, we will provide you with access for any purpose including a request that we correct the data if it is inaccurate or delete the data if Cyanogen is not required to retain it by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may decline to process requests that are frivolous/vexatious, jeopardize the privacy of others, are extremely impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law. Access, correction, or deletion requests can be made in writing to Cyanogen Inc., 516 High Street, Palo Alto, California 94301, Attention: Legal Department /Personal Information Request. 

### 5\. Children

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 except where a parent has set up an account for their child and provided Cyanogen with verified parental consent. If we learn that we have collected the personal information of a child under 13 without first receiving verifiable parental consent we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible. 

### 6\. Location-Based Services

To provide location-based services, Cyanogen and our partners and licensees may collect, use, and share precise location data, including the real-time geographic location of your product or device. This location data is collected anonymously in a form that does not personally identify you and is used by Cyanogen and our partners and licensees to provide and improve location-based products and services. For example, we may share geographic location with application providers when you opt in to their location services. 

### 7\. Third-Party Sites and Services

Cyanogen websites, products, applications, and services may contain links to third-party websites, products, and services. Our products and services may also use or offer products or services from third parties. Information collected by third parties, which may include such things as location data or contact details, is governed by their privacy practices. We encourage you to learn about the privacy practices of those third parties. 

### 8\. Our Companywide Commitment to Your Privacy

To make sure your personal information is secure, we communicate our privacy and security guidelines to Cyanogen employees and strictly enforce privacy safeguards within the company. 

### 9\. Privacy Questions

If you have any questions or concerns about Cyanogen's Privacy Policy or data processing or if you would like to make a complaint about a possible breach of local privacy laws, please contact us at Cyanogen Inc., 516 High Street, Palo Alto, California 94301, Attention: Legal Department, Privacy Policy. 

All such communications are examined and replies issued where appropriate as soon as possible. If you are unsatisfied with the reply received, you may refer your complaint to the relevant regulator in your jurisdiction. If you ask us, we will endeavor to provide you with information about relevant complaint avenues which may be applicable to your circumstances. 

Cyanogen may update its Privacy Policy from time to time. When we change the policy in a material way, a notice will be posted on our website along with the updated Privacy Policy. 

### 10\. Cyanogen's California Do Not Track Notice

Cyanogen does not track its customers over time and across third party websites to provide targeted advertising and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals. However, some third party sites do keep track of your browsing activities when they serve you content, which enables them to tailor what they present to you. If you are visiting such sites, Safari allows you to set the DNT signal on your browser so that third parties (particularly advertisers) know you do not want to be tracked. 

_Notice to California Residents:_ If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information by Cyanogen to affiliated and unaffiliated third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. With respect to these entities, this privacy policy applies only to their activities within the State of California. To make such a request, please write us at Cyanogen Inc., 516 High Street, Palo Alto, California 94301, Attention: Legal Department/California Civil Code Section 1798.83.
